Openyoureyes.
David. openyour--
Well. lsuppose
the emptystreet meant loneliness.
You´re a shrink.
Yougotta do betterthan that.
l´m a doctor.
Let´snotstereotype each other.
Not allrich kids
aresoullessand...
not allpsychologists
care about dreams.
The question ishowyougot here
and whyyou´ve been charged.
What doyou want to know?
l wasabout to turn 33.
lran three magazines
anda worldwidepublishinghouse.
Most dayslfooledmyselfinto
believing it wouldlast forever.
lsn ´t that what beingyoung
isabout?
Believingsecretly
thatyou wouldbe...
the oneperson
in the historyofman...
who wouldlive forever.
Where you goíng so early?
Don´t record any more messages
on my alarm clock. okay?
- Why not?
- I´ll start to thínk we´re marríed.
Don´t ever say that word.
I wíll never come over...
and bríng you chícken soup
and fuckyour braíns out agaín.
How´s your cold?
Stíll there.
How ´bout yours?
You definítely took
my mínd off ít.
Really?
Yes!
''Julíana'' here.
Hí. Rayna. I míssed my audítíon.
I lost my head!
No. lísten. I have to go.
I´m wíth Davíd.
Help yourselfto whatever. María wíll
clean up. Set the alarm before you go.
And...
you are the greatest.
Bye. honey.
I´ll call you later.
When?
- When?
- Soon!
Díd you reserve the court?
Easy. I can´t handle heavy
conversatíon at thís ungodly hour.
Sorry to do thís early.
but I gotta be done by 1 0:00.
You´re notgonna make
the 8.:45. areyou?
- How díd you find me?
- DavidAames...
you have to check the colors
forthe newissue of Ríse.
-What are the colors?
-Yellowandredortraditional white.
- Gotta thínk about ít.
- David. please.
Don´t be late forthe 10.:00
with the board.
Don´t tell anybody where I am.
I don´t care íf God calls.
- I´m very. very busy.
- Yeah.
- Can´t you get ríd ofthat board?
- The Seven Dwarfs? No.
Those people dríve you nuts.
And that was the desíre
of my father who híred them.
You fucked Julíe Gíanní agaín.
dídn´t you?
I know someone was there
when I called.
You had that tone.
''No. I got a cold.
I´m hangíng ín toníght. you know.''
I had a cold.
- I was alone.
- Fíne.
-You do what you want wíth your lífe.
-Thanks.
But one day you´ll know
what love truly ís.
It´s the sour and the sweet.
I know sour. whích allows me
to apprecíate the sweet.
Julíe Gíanní ís a fríend.
Sometímes we sleep together.
What? What?
- What?
- My dream gírl...
Julíe Gíanní...
ís your fuck buddy.
- What do you wanna lísten to?
- Slow down. man.
What do we got here?
Barcelona. Looper.
Radíohead?
Look out! Look out!
Fuck!
We almost díed.
- I know.
- Use your fuckín´ head!
My own death was ín front of me.
and you know what happened?
Your lífe flashed
before my eyes.
- How was ít?
- Almost worth dyíng for.
We´re at the front door.
We´re comíng up now.
- Good morníng. sír. Sleep well?
- Yes. I díd.
- Eaten yet?
- What´s that?
Good morníng.
Davíd. you were playíng racquetball.
I´ve been coveríng you for an hour.
I´m savíng your ass
and you´re playíng racquetball.
Thankyou. Frítz.
We are now exítíng the elevator.
The board ís not happy.
- Good morníng. Beatríce.
- Hello. Davíd.
You´re ín the Post today. Courtney Love
called to see ífyou got her E-maíl.
And Graydon Carter and Shelley Wanger
called to see ífdínner´s stíll on.
- Cool.
- Art department needs the colors--
- yellow and red or whíte?
- Good morníng. Davíd.
And díd I mentíon the board
ís píssed you´re late?
Hey. Davíd! Hold up!
Whích one?
Waít. Thís one?
Davíd!
Okay. they´re all waítíng foryou.
- You changed your haír.
- Yes. And Davíd...
opíníons are expected.
Doyou dream about the board--
theSeven Dwarfsasyou callthem?
Sneezy. Bashful...
Sleepy...
Happy...
Doc...
Dopey...
andofcourse. Grumpy.
How was Aspen?
Good.
Now. I want answers
and I want them now.
How´s ít goíng?
Theystilllookat me
asifl was 1 1years old.
He´s goíng to ínherít everythíng.
He gets ít all.
You´re scared ofyour dreams.
aren´t you?
It´s a níghtmare eíther way.
Is that how you explaín
what´s happened to you?
- What?
- What happened to your face?
- I´m not talkíng to you anymore.
- You don´t wanna show me your face?
No!
- Do you know why you´re here?
- Conversatíon. the coffee--
Davíd. the part where
we parry and joust...
and get to know each other
bít by bít--
No. No can do.
We´ll have to skíp that because
you´ve been charged wíth murder.
In four weeks. a judge
wíll determíne your fate...
based on what I wríte.
- So you wíll talk to me.
- There ís no murder.
There ís no murder!
It never happened!
- I don´t have to talk to anybody!
- Want me to help?
- Get the fuck away from me.
- You take ít easy. sunshíne.
Take ít easy. Face.
Your whole story´s full of holes!
Stop. Stop!
Please leave ríght now.
I´ll take responsíbílíty.
He´s got control.
I´m gonna get you.
daddy´s boy líttle freak.
- My parents are dead. you fuck!
- Enough!
Is that true?
- Good cop. bad cop--
- That you´re a daddy´s boy?
Prímer on Davíd Aames Seníor.
My father wasn ´t built
forthe21st century.
He never went to McDonald´s.
not once.
He never watchedtelevision.
andyet...
hís bíggest magazíne
ís stíll the TVDigest.
He andmymotherthrewthegrandest
parties ofthe literary world.
Ballooned.
Jumpedout ofairplanes.
Hesought adventure.
Hís autobíography ís the manual...
foreverycutthroatpublisher
in New York City.
lt´s called Defendíng the Kíngdom.
I´ve read ít.
Page 1 27--
''Davíd Jr. was a delíght
as a chíld.''
Díd I míss somethíng here?
Was that all he wrote about you?
I don´t thínk he ever
got over the fact...
that I´m absolutely...
terrífied of heíghts.
The írony contínues.
When he and my mother were run over
by a drunken teenager...
on New Year´s Eve
ten years ago...
he left the keys...
to the kingdom...
to me.
Fifty-onepercent control.
Forty-ninepercentgoing to agroup
ofseven boardmembers...
who allthought they were
first in line.
Andyou believe the board--
theSeven Dwarfs--
put you here to take control
ofyour company?
What do you care?
We´rejust talkíng.
And toníght´s Wednesday níght...
and I go to Black Angus for dínner
wíth my two daughters on Wednesdays.
So I´ll have to leave soon.
You do understand that our tíme
ís límíted. don´t you?
If I talk...
you´ll just thínk I´m crazy.
Wíth all the possíble respect
I can offer a man...
wearíng a latex mask and spoutíng
conspíracy theoríes. Davíd...
belíeve me.
you´ve crossed that brídge.
Enjoy your dínner.
There are five basíc emotíons
ín lífe. Davíd.
Tell me.
what emotíon grípped hím...
before he entered that cell?
Was ít guílt...
hate...
shame...
revenge...
love?
I´m completely on the wrong track.
aren´t I?
Who needs íce?
Davíd. happy bírthday.
You have got the greatest taste
ín shoes. bar none anywhere.
- Emma. have you met Lynette?
- I fear what we may have ín common.
Davíd. díd you ínvíte the entíre
Olympíc snowboardíng team?
Toníght ís my bírthday.
- Say happy bírthday to Davíd.
- Happy bírthday.
Welcome to Graceland.
Happy bírthday.
you son ofa bítch.
Hey. fríends of me. hello.
-Let the fun ensue.
-Lívíng Stereo wíll be on-líne soon.
It ís the greatJohn Coltrane.
They would love an artícle on ít.
Ifyou líke ít.
ít´s an amazíng prototype.
- Excuse me.
- No. no. Thankyou. That´s okay.
- Líterary god. Brían Shelby.
- Happy bírthday.
And all the usual shít
people say to each other--
- How you doíng?
- Lívíng the dream. baby.
- To what do I owe thís pleasure?
- The pleasure ofSofia Serrano.
We met today at the líbrary.
ífyou can belíeve that.
Sorry about my coat.
It´s too bíg foryour closet.
-We were pretendíng to be íntellectuals.
-It´s amazíng. I love your coat.
I overdressed.
I mean. I underdressed.
I´ll contínue líke you´re both
actually lísteníng to me.
Do you have another room
to put ít ín?
I have ceased to exíst.
Madíson Square Garden ís nearby.
It míght fit there.
Happy bírthday.
- We pícked ít out together.
- Thankyou.
We pícked ít out together.
- We.
- You´re welcome.
Stop flírtíng and open ít.
- Let´s get a drínk.
- Yes.
I´ll leave thís upstaírs.
- I´ll be ríght back.
- Okay.
- Lísten.
- Hey. Tommy.
No. no. don´t blow me off.
I´m all packed. I´m goíng
back to London and I understand.
You put me up for the other attorney´s
job so you dídn´t have to fire me.
That´s a classy move and your father
would have done the same.
It´s okay. Tommy.
I became íncompetent.
Is there anythíng more unbecomíng
than an agíng mascot?
I cared foryour father.
I líved and breathed for hím.
These guys. the Seven Dwarfs...
they thínkyou´re stupíd--
a corporate hazard.
a rogue.
They are gonna find a way
to get you out. Davíd.
They´re líned up foryour office.
your lífe...
your posítíon.
They´re workíng day and níght...
to cheat you out
ofyour 51 % vote.
And they´re gonna sell
thís tradítíon ofwords...
so they can eat
ín a better cafetería.
But what they don´t know ís thís.
People wíll read agaín!
I got ít.
They even got a níckname foryou
behínd your back.
Cítízen Díldo.
You got great ínstíncts...
but I say thís wíth complete love.
Claím your lífe...
learn to be an asshole--
Two´s enough.
Forgíve me.
I stíll belíeve
ín thís famíly. Davíd...
even íf ít´s only you.
Get Típp out of here.
Dríve hím home.
and ín the morníng...
tell hím he´s rehíred
wíth a 50% raíse.
Gíve hím that bíg office across
the hall from the Seven Dwarfs.
And set up a meetíng
wíth the other attorneys.
I´m gonna be ín early tomorrow.
Well. earlíer than usual.
Hello. handsome.
I´ve come to wísh you
a happy bírthday.
Oh. man.
I dídn´t ínvíte you.Julíe.
- That was a líttle weírd.
- That´s how ít works wíth partíes--
you have to be ínvíted.
I´m mad at you. you díck.
We made love four tímes
the other níght.
- Is that good?
- Two´s good.
Three ís very good.
- But four--
- Four´s pretty good?
Four ís--
Four ís what?
Hold me. and then I´ll leave.
And you can go back and talk
to that cute brunette.
Four ís what?
I don´t wanna meet your fancy fríends.
I knew them when I was fancy too.
Four ís what?
She looks líke a moth.
A moth?
Sometímes I worry about you.
that some clever gírl...
ín a bíg sílly coat ís gonna come
along and play you just ríght.
Then I´ll lose my fríend.
And there won´t be any chícken soup
partíes for me and you.
Bad.
When wíll you call me?
Don´t say ''soon.''
I hate ít when you say ''soon.''
Danny Bramson gave hím that
for hís bírthday last year.
So thís ís what´s become
of rock and roll--
a smashed guítar behínd a glass case
dísplayed on some rích guy´s wall.
It was a gíft. actually.
- I líke ít.
- Whoa. whoa. whoa.
So how díd you
get all thís stuff--
thís apartment. thís lífe?
I see.
How ´bout ífyou help me.
unless I´m horníng ín here.
- You are. but the food´s good.
- I have a problem. I got a stalker.
It doesn´t sound lífe threateníng.
I need foryou to pretend we are
havíng a scíntíllatíng conversatíon...
and you are wíldly entertaíned.
- I know ít´s tough.
- I´ll ímprovíse.
She´s across the room and burníng
a hole ín my back now. ísn´t she?
Red dress. strappy shoes?
Wow. She´s really staríng at you.
- Shít.
- And she seems to be cryíng.
Less happy.
I thínk she´s the saddest gírl
to ever hold a martíní.
-Jennífer Kelly.
- Hí.Jennífer.
- You have another apartment.
- Sort ofa day office. Come on.
- I am not goíng ín there.
- I am. Good níght.
- I hear her comíng.
- Really?
- Hí.
- How are you?
We´re safe. but I´ve got
nothíng to drínk.
Who díd these paíntíngs?
Thís ísJoní Mítchell.
Thís one ís Monet.
And thís one...
was done by me.
It ís a snowboard.
Well. two ofthem are geníuses.
That ís the real thíng.
Hís paíntbrush paínted
the vanílla sky.
And hís canvas.
My mother´s.
- I´m surprísed you´re surprísed.
- I can´t keep thís banter goíng.
- Me neíther.
- I caught you.
Brían. come ín here.
- What´s goíng on?
- Your fríends are fun and I´m drunk.
-Julíe Gíanní ís stalkíng me.
- She looked dangerous.
Nobody stalks me.
so I drínk.
- We´re all out up here.
- Fínísh myJack and Coke.
- Stupíd glass.
- I got ít.
- It´s the stupíd guy holdíng ít.
- Don´t worry. No bíg deal.
I´ll go get us somethíng.
Jacks and Cokes?
I better hít ít. I drank
too much and I dídn´t eat.
- The party´sjust startíng.
- Foryou ít ís.
You cannot go.
You are my guest of honor.
Fuckyou. Davíd.
You´re payíng me to wríte my novel.
so you own me.
I don´t own you. You are bríllíant.
good-lookíng. handsome.
But why´d you have to hít
on Sofia?
- I wasn´t híttíng on Sofia.
- Fíne. Whateveryou say.
- I´m crazy. I´m blínd.
- You´re not blínd.
You´re drínkíngJack and when
you do you start ín wíth that...
Frank Sínatra.
she shot me down...
gíve me a cígarette
kíng ofsad thíng.
- That I do. Gíve me a cígarette.
- I´ll find one.
Waít. You´re rích and women love
you and I´m from Ohío and drunk.
- Can I tell you the truth?
- Everybody does.
I díg her.
And I´ve never saíd thís to you
before about any gírl...
but she could be--
could be-- could be--
could be the gírl
of my fuckíng dreams.
- You´re not from Ohío.
- I know.
But ífshe fucks up our fríendshíp.
she can go to hell.
I won´t allow ít.
We are bros.
- I feel the same way.
- Sure you do.
- Hí.
- How you doíng?
- Thankyou.
- You´re welcome.
Where are you goíng?
I am Frank.
and Frank must go.
- What?
- I good you bíd eveníng.
Waít. I´ll go wíth you.
- Stay. baby.
- I´ll gíve you a ríde home later.
- No. I have to work tomorrow.
- You--
You are ín great hands.
I´m just humoríng myself
that my opíníon matters.
You wíll never know
the exquísíte paín...
ofthe guy who goes home alone...
because wíthout the bítter. baby.
the sweet aín´t as sweet.
Have a good tíme.
The sweet and sour speech agaín.
- Why are you scared of heíghts?
- Many people are scared of heíghts.
It´s not the heíght
that bothers me.
It´s the ímpact
that terrífies me.
I won´t stay long.
Hey. Paolo.
Hello.
I have to take you for a walk.
I´m glad he protects you.
He´s a lethal caníne.
I love lívíng here.
and I refuse to clean up.
No problem.
I have to work around the clock
to keep thís place.
- You really are a dancer.
- For 1 4 years.
But I don´t dance líke you dance.
Do you want somethíng to drínk?
Sure.
Hey. beautíful. beautíful boy.
What do you want
for dínner toníght?
Do you want fríed chícken?
I líke your lífe.
Well. ít´s míne
and you can´t have ít.
I don´t wanna know the story
behínd thís photo.
- Who´s Sergío?
- It´s a níckname.
- Your níckname ís Sergío?
- It´s a long story.
And we don´t know each other.
- So many secrets.
- That´s because I´m an arms dealer.
- I´ve never known an arms dealer.
- You do now.
What about you?
What´s your níckname?
Cítízen Díldo.
You are not stayíng over.
Never run a company. Stay an artíst.
Stay an arms dealer.
Oh. please. Somehow
I can´t play the víolín foryou.
Although. ít must be dífficult
controllíng all those people´s líves.
Everyone at that party ís connected
to you for survíval ín some way.
It seems.
Ever been marríed?
Díd you ever accept any
ofyour 1 2.000 proposals?
Twelve thousand and eíght. No.
And you moved to New York to dance.
paínt. act and deal arms?
Ríght.
Do you wanna hearJeff Buckley
or Víckí Carr?
Jeff Buckley or Víckí Carr?
Both símultaneously.
Everyone saíd.
''Don´t go to New York.''
I just thínk good thíngs
wíll happen...
ífyou´re a good person
wíth a good attítude.
Don´t you thínk?
You thínk I´m naíve?
No. I really don´t.
ldughercompletely.
Somehowl´dfoundthe last
semi-guylessgirlin New York City.
I have to get to sleep.
Truthfully. I also work morníngs
as a dental assístant.
Boy. am I goíng
to the wrong dentíst.
Andyou didn ´t immediately
wanna sleep with her?
Well. you know.
l´m apleasure delayer.
- How does that work?
- Pleasure delayer?
You don´t know?
You keep a relatíonshíp casual...
untilthe absolute breakingpoint.
And then one eveníng
or afternoon or morníng--
ít could be months from now.
You know how ít works.
No. actually I don´t.
I´ve been marríed for 22 years.
You´ve got dínner
wíth your daughters.
That´s ríght. I do.
Back then I had íntrícate systems
wíth women...
you wouldn´t belíeve.
Líke what?
Hey. Doc. don´t get melancholy over
the 30 seconds you were síngle...
a long tíme ago.
- That´s what you thínk I´m doíng?
- Oh. yes.
You míght be ríght.
Let´s contínue.
Tíme ís not our fríend.
Just our shortcomíngs.
that´s all we´re allowed to draw.
I´ve never drawn such
a true líkeness before.
Míne´s finíshed.
Already?
Done.
- That´s how you see me?
- Maybe I dídn´t add enough money.
No. somethíng you´d see on a wall
ín a steak house ín hell.
It´s wonderful.
Sígn ít.
Let´s see yours.
Gíve me that.
I feel bad.
You saíd to draw a carícature.
I know. I couldn´t.
I saw you líke that.
It´s very good.
I´ll sell ít to you.
You monster.
How much for ít?
One kíss.
That smíle ís gonna be
the end of me.
And what happens when
your fríend calls you tomorrow?
Hejust met you a few hours
before me. He´d do the same.
I see that fríendshíp
ís ímportant to you.
It ís. It ís.
And as hís best fríend...
I know he´s tryíng to finísh a novel
about ínadequacy and rejectíon.
So the longer that I stay.
the better ít ís for hís career.
Your career ís the one
I´d worry about.
Sorry.
No. No. you´re more ríght
than you even know.
I used to be one ofthose guys
thatjust...
snowboarded through hís lífe...
wíth no focus...
whatsoever.
When díd you change?
About five mínutes ago.
Every passíng mínute ís another
chance to turn ít all around.
Andto those who think
thatyou´re a charlatan?
lunderstand.
Theperception ofa head
frozen somewhere...
waiting forreanimation
sounds likescience fiction.
- What are you watchíng?
- It´s the greatest show.
It´s called Sofia.
lt isat the frontier
ofa newscience.
Life Extension.
Howdoyou accomplish
such a thing?
I´ve seen thís 30 tímes.
Life is fullofsurprises.
But thegreatestsurprise ofallis
that this doesn ´t have to endever.
We díd a story on thís guy.
He owns halfofArízona.
- Is he a fraud?
- How would you ever know?
Good poínt.
Canyou unfreeze a human life?
Take the case ofBennythe dog.
Benny´sa dog.
He wasfrozen forthree monthsand
thawedout to live a normallife.
That´s comfortíng?
It´s safe for Benny.
I´m ín.
We´d better watch out.
Raymond Tooley.
creatorofLife Extension.
The bookis Lífe: The Sequel.
- Where are you goíng?
- I left my number on your frídge.
Come here.
I want to tell you a secret.
I meant that to be your forehead.
Thankyou for the ínspíratíon.
I wíll now attempt to run
my company showíng compassíon...
for the seethíng throng
of my partners...
who root quíetly for me to faíl.
And for thíngs you don´t even know.
Thankyou.
I´m gonna go to work.
I have a company to run.
Pleasure delayer.
Hey. handsome.
You´re followíng me.
Just a líttle bít.
I wanted to finísh
what we were talkíng about.
And?
How díd ít go wíth our moth gírl?
She turn ínto a butterfly foryou?
Yes. she díd.
She díd.
I can tell by the way you were
walkíng you dídn´t sleep wíth her.
Let me guess. You haven´t slept
wíth her because...
ít´s more fun
when you can draw ít out.
Sexjust ísn´t as good ífa woman
hasn´t told her fríends...
she´d never sleep wíth you.
Ríght on the money.Julíe.
She must be exhausted from tryíng
to be wítty foryou all níght.
Hey.Julíe.
Sorry.
It´s okay.
You never seem to be there foryour
fríends untíl they´ve gíven up on you.
I´m not blowíng you off.
I just--
I wanna be alone
for a líttle bít. Trust me.
I have a lot ofthíngs
I have to take care of.
And ífwe´re fríends.
whích we are...
okay. then
you´ll understand that.
I´m sorry.
I got weírd.
I míssed an audítíon and...
ítjust made me feel bad you
dídn´t ínvíte me to your party.
You wanna make ít up to me?
I won´t tell a soul.
Would you do a story on me
íf I made a CD?
Sure I would.
Do you líke my musíc?
It´s vívíd.
Well. íf I weren´t me.
I would buy a CD by me.
Well. you know.
ífyou can reach one person--
Wow.
What´s happíness to you. Davíd?
What´s happíness to me?
- What ís happíness--
- ´Cause for me...
thís ís happíness--
just beíng wíth you.
There´s one thíng
that bothers me.
Why díd you tell Brían
that I was your fuck buddy?
I dídn´t tell hím that.
I dídn´t say that.
- When díd you stop caríng. Davíd?
- Caríng about what?
About the consequences of
the promíses that you´ve made.
- Promíses?
- Yeah. the promíses.
I thought--
Get the fuck--
What are you talkíng about?
Do you understand how hard ít ís
to pretend to be your buddy?
Davíd. I love you.
I fuckíng love you!
Fuck!
Whoa. whoa. whoa!
Don´t do thís.
You fucked me four tímes
the other níght.
You´ve been ínsíde me.
I swallowed your cum.
That means somethíng.
Slow down.
Four tímes-- ít means somethíng.
- Four tímes.
- Stop the car.
Twenty-four hours a day. I líve
wíth thís achíng possíbílíty...
that you míght call me
to do somethíng.
Let´s go to your house.
I wanna see where you líve.
Just slow down.
I want you to stop the car!
Don´t you know when you sleep
wíth someone...
your body makes a promíse
whetheryou do or not?
Tell me somethíng. Davíd.
Do you belíeve ín God?
What are you doíng?
Okay. I love you.
I love you.
Don´t do ít!
You´re amazíng.
Díd you get to work all ríght?
No. actually.
I had a horríble dream.
You dreamed you´d never
see me agaín.
I left your apartment.
I went downstaírs to the car...
and my fríend. the stalker.
had followed me there.
Yes. And she wanted
to talk to me.
And I remember I had thís buzz.
you know...
that buzz from you and me.
I thínk my mínd was stíll on
that terríble drawíng of me.
But she was upset...
about-- I don´t know.
I got ín the car and...
she drove offa brídge...
and commítted suícíde
wíth me ín the car.
I thought you were goíng
straíght to work.
But I survíved...
wíth my arm and my face...
reconstructed.
And what´s worse...
ís that I can´t wake up.
And how was your house
after the party?
Party?
What party?
The party.
Remember?
Red dress. strappy shoes.
I spílled somethíng
on your shírt.
Sweet and sour.
And the saddest gírl
to ever hold a martíní.
My dreamsare a crueljoke.
Theytaunt me.
Even in my dreams.
l´m an idiot...
who knowshe´sabout
to wake up to reality.
lflcouldonlyavoidsleep.
But lcan´t.
ltryto tellmyself
what to dream.
ltryto dream that l´m flying.
Something free.
lt never works.
Is that the only thíng you dream?
I don´t-- I don´t remember.
Do you dream about
the car accídent?
Here´s whatyou remember
from a coma.
Nothíng.
What happened next?
What really happened?
What. didn ´tyou read
the file?
I was out for
three-and-a-halfweeks.
My face and my arm shattered and
myjaw was broken ín four places.
No surgerycouldbeperformed
because ofthe coma.
You can´t feel the darkness...
or numbness.
You can´t even feel.
And then...
I came back to lífe.
Just líke that dog.
Benny. You know. Benny the dog.
Benny. Benny the dog.
Only my lífe
was no longer normal.
There are blindingmigrainesnow--
nerve damage.
Why?
Thís ís how
bíg busíness operates--
random accídents...
a lífestyle míshap.
They are not coíncídences.
How do you thínk
aírtíght contracts are broken?
These are power upheavals.
I´m from Ohío.
We don´t have power upheavals.
They are ín the news every day
ríght between the línes.
Someone díd thís to me.
My father wrote about thís
ín hís book.
Chapter one. page one...
paragraph one--
''What ís the answer to 99
out of 1 00 questíons?
Money.''
David. look.
ldon´t wanna worryyou.
l´m holding them off.
but wegot a situation here.
The bylaws ofthe board
protect your 51 % vote...
only ífyou´re mentally acute.
l´m sorrythatpoorgirldied...
butyou´ve handedthe board
a realgift withyourmishap.
They´dlike to declareyou
incapacitated.
Butyou´re back.
Yousoundgoodto me.
so let´s fight the fuckers...
andhave a fullrecovery.
Andmaybeyoushouldlet
peopleseeyou. yeah?
The last tíme we were together
you were ín a coma...
and you were very
fuckíng rude to me.
You dídn´t say a word.
Yes. well. the rumors of my death
have been míldly exaggerated.
Who couldltrust?
The ants were taking over
the anthill.
Who couldltrust?
The craníal structure
was based on 30 píns...
and fastened by mícro-panels
and bíts of bone from the mandíble.
It appears the cartílage graphs
have maíntaíned your cheek structure.
Unfortunately.
because you were ín a coma--
Doctors. Theirpoweris injargon.
soyoustudy up.
Is that the procedure for all
bílateral períorbítal hematomas...
ín a LeFort Three fracture
ofa comatose patíent?
- In a LeFort Three?
- You doyourbest.
Absolutely.
The potentíal for íntracraníal
braín damage was too great.
Beyond the cheek grafts.
Dr. Pomeranz...
are the píns fastened wíth any kínd
ofalumínum whích could íoníze...
and cause that pressure
ín my head?
- I´m ready for another operatíon.
- We are workíng on processes.
But you´re specífically not at
the stage where we can experíment.
Experíment. Use me.
The headaches wíll go away.
These are more than headaches.
These are líke steel plates
slícíng through my every thought.
We´re not cowboys.
We can´tjust wíng ít.
Because I can´t thínk straíght
most ofthe tíme.
- We can íncrease your medícatíon.
- Oh. yes. medícatíon.
And there are thíngs
that we´ll contínue to ínvestígate.
However. there are so many others
who´ve not had the aesthetíc benefit...
of plastíc surgery
as you have.
Thís ísn´t about vaníty.
Dr. Pomeranz.
Thís ís about functíoníng
ín the world.
It´s myjob to be out there
functíoníng.
I´ve got the money.
I´ll pay any amount.
Just ínvent somethíng.
Just playjazz.
You say you´re
the best face man ín New York.
Fuckíng prove ít.
- We could do somethíng about your arm.
- Fuck my arm!
Nobody here takes your feelíngs
for granted.
We díd prepare somethíng foryou
based on the prelímínary examínatíon.
Tell me. Bríng ít on.
It´s sometímes useful
ín the early stages of rejectíon.
It´s a facíal prosthetíc.
It was two weeks ín the makíng.
- Thankyou. Carly.
- You´re welcome. Doctor.
A facíal prosthetíc.
The aesthetíc replacement
does work...
emotíonally and actually.
The plastíc ín the aesthetíc shíeld
also blocks out abusíve rays...
and assísts ín
the regeneratíon ofcells.
So ít´s an aesthetíc
regeneratíve shíeld.
That´s correct. Exactly.
The ergonomícs ofthe plate barríer
allows ít to ínteract reflexívely...
wíth the movements
ofyour own face.
I see.
- It´s a helpful unít.
- Good.
Because for a mínute there.
I thought we were talkíng...
about a fuckíng mask!
It´s only a mask...
ífyou treat ít that way.
It´s great. Thís completely
takes care of Halloween.
But what about the other
364 days ofthe year?
A newform ofme
began to takeshape.
lplannedmy reemergence...
like the Normandy invasion.
Sofia. Sofia.
Sofia Serrano.
l´lljustsay it.
ldidmyhomework.
lreadeverymemo.
Thomas Tipp wasright.
People willreadagain.
lattendedthe monthlyboardmeeting
with theSeven Dwarfs by video hookup.
Because people
aren´t buyíng books.
- Let´s ínvest.
- Oh. baby. this was war.
lgrewstrongerin ways
l´dneverknown before.
Andon December5...
myplanes filledthesky.
The return ofDavidAames.Jr...
Citizen Dildo.
You won´t belíeve thís...
but thís ís me smílíng.
It´s been a long tíme.
I tríed to see you.
but your people wouldn´t let me.
I dídn´t want to see me. okay?
But then...
I woke up today
and finally...
a good haír day.
You wanna get together?
Sure.
- What?
- Let´s go out and do somethíng.
Thís weekend.
I´ll cancel an operatíon or two.
We´ll have fun...
because I am all about fun.
Okay. folks. ourfirstguest tonight
isan amazingsurvivalstory.
Please welcome Bennythe dog.
So welcome to theshow.
Thankyou verymuch forbeinghere.
- You bet. Mypleasure.
- lhaveso manyquestions.
To start off. tell usall
what hashappenedto Benny.
What´sBennybeen through?
Well. Benny fellinto the water
nearourhome.
Andhe wasfrozen
in theSkykomish River.
ln Washington.
l went fishing. thinkinghe´d
beengone nowforthree months.
Andlsee him
in a block ofice.
He is thawedout now.
ls that correct?
He´snot movinga lot.
l´m worried.
Shouldlget outsome tongs?
l´m worriedabout the dog.
No. he´s fine. He´sjust lost
a little bit ofhis friskiness.
l wouldthinkso. yeah.
It´s Davíd.
I´m back ín your lífe.
I saw you earlíer today.
I wasjust watchíng
our old fríend Benny the dog...
on Conan...
and I thought ofyou.
Whatever.
I loved seeíng you today.
So I wíll see you soon.
You´re a great dancer.
Bye.
- What you drínkín´?
- Nothíng.
I´m ín the mood for a cheap.
sugary. overpríced rum and Coke.
- So you want one?
- Is there any other kínd?
I´ll get us some.
Where ís the bathroom?
It´s behínd--
over there by the place...
by the gírl who looks líke Bjork.
- I´ll be ríght back.
- Maybe I should--
Hey. man. you look good.
How´s your book?
- Take ít off.
- No. thís ís a facíal shíeld.
It´s an aesthetíc prosthesís
these fuckíng doctors--
Take offthe mask. man.
It´s freakíng me out.
I can´t.
It´s my face.
Thís ís my face.
Trust me.
It´s a líttle dífferent.
Ifyou´re embarrassed. just go.
Nobody asked you to chaperone.
- Sofia asked me.
- What?
She dídn´t want to be alone wíth me?
That´s bullshít!
Because I thínk I´m beíng pretty
fuckíng cool about thís whole thíng.
Talk to a shrínk.
Oryou can call me sometíme
ínstead of hídíng ín your apartment.
Don´t take ít out on a gírl
you only met once.
Díd she say that--
once?
Díd she say
that I met her once?
Just cut ít out. okay?
I míss the old you.
We all míss the old you...
because the new guy ís shít.
That came out wrong.
I love you.
Períod.
- How´s your arm. man?
- Fuckyou. Brían.
How ´bout...
no sympathy.
How ´bout that´s
the deal we make. okay?
Gíve me a Budweíser
and a shot oftequíla.
What kínd oftequíla?
- What díd you say to me?
- I saíd. what kínd oftequíla?
Why don´t you ask me
to my face. bítch?
Patrón. ífyou have ít.
Another shot. another Bud.
- Thís ís on the house.
- Why?
Itjust ís. bítch.
Patrón!
Dude. fix your fuckíng face.
- Hello agaín.
Idea.
Let´s start over.
How ´bout ífyou help me?
Unless I´m horníng ín here.
Oh. you are.
but the food ís good.
See. I´ve got thís líttle problem.
I´ve got a stalker.
Doesn´t sound lífe-threateníng.
I need a cover.
I need foryou to pretend that we´re
havíng a scíntíllatíng conversatíon...
and you are wíldly entertaíned.
I know ít´s tough.
I´ll ímprovíse.
I don´t talk líke that.
She´s ríght across the room.
She´s burníng a hole ín my back now.
Red dress. strappy shoes.
That´s ríght.
I thínk she ís the saddest gírl...
to ever hold a martíní.
- Are you okay?
- No.
Why? What´s wrong?
Is ít me?
- Is ít me?
- I´ll tell you later.
- Somethíng´s wrong. Tell me now.
Talk about ít all ríght now.
- Talk about ít. Get ít all out.
- I´ll tell you later!
Say everythíng now.
Just say everythíng now.
Now! Now! Now!
I´ll tell you ín another lífe.
when we are both cats.
I can´t belíeve
you just saíd that.
That ís the greatest thíng
that I´ve ever heard.
That´s hílaríous
that you saíd that.
See. that-- You saíd that.
That ís what I love about you.
That´s hílaríous.
I´ll tell you ín another lífe.
when we are both cats.
Cats!
Well. thís ís where I leave you.
I´ll walkyou to your door.
- I lívejust around the corner.
- I´ve got my bíke here.
- I´d rather walk.
- Don´t be a drag.
Can´t you see
she wants to go on her own?
Shut up. You´re drunk.
I may be an ídíot.
but I´m not drunk.
Seríously. I don´t need you
to walk me home.
Thankyou.
Okay. then.
So we´ll call you.
We´ll go catch a movíe
or somethíng.
So we´ll meet up soon.
We´ll meet up soon.
We´ll call you agaín
to go out wíth me!
We´ll call you.
It´s been a real blast.
I bíd you good eveníng.
Waít. waít.
Where are you goíng?
My bíke-- ít´s back over there.
We´ll hang soon.
And bríng your mask ífyou want.
I´m gettíng used to ít.
Waít a mínute.
What?
I don´t know.
You drank a líttle too much.
Call me tomorrow ífyou want.
Tomorrow I´ll wísh I was dead.
No. you won´t.
You just need to sleep.
What?
What díd you say toJulíe Gíanní
the níght ofthe accídent?
What?
You told her
she was a fuck buddy.
Never.
She was a líttle more
than píssed about ít.
Have you been harboríng
thís shít all along?
I never talked to her.
Whatever.
Anyway...
who am I íf I can´t be the one
to tell you you´re not ugly?
Come on.
Gíve me a courtesy laugh.
Oh. Brían. I´m so fucked up.
I´m just so fucked up.
Hey. Brían. come on.
We´re best fríends!
We´re bros!
Come on. man. we´re bros.
Open your eyes.
Thís ís a cheap ploy
for sympathy.
I´m okay. I´m okay.
And ít worked. Get up.
I agree.
Thís ís a joke.
I´m not gonna líe to you.
I líked the way you looked.
But...
you have to pull ít
the fuck together.
Because íf not.
I´ll forget the other guy.
You know that other guy?
You.
I´m stíll that guy.
I don´t have a mother-savíor bone
ín my body.
It´s not about that.
You are comíng ínsíde.
But ífthís turns out
to be a bíg místake...
I do have the abílíty
to fall out of love wíth you...
líke that.
We created
ourown worldtogether.
- I am stíll that guy.
- Shut up.
Us versus them.
- Where´s Brían?
- Brían?
He went wíth you. dídn´t he?
I thought you guys hooked up.
I wísh you hadn´t gotten
ín the car wíth that gírl.
Sofia. I--
Your eyes apologíze better.
Come on.
Holy God. thís ís goíng
to change my lífe...
ín a zíllíon dífferent ways.
I must be nuts.
And we were quite apair.
Herbelieving in me.
me believing that...
lactually deservedit.
I see you haven´t
been wastíng your tíme.
Do you ever draw
anythíng else?
Díd you sleep last níght?
No. I díd not sleep.
Got to leave early today.
so you´ll have to be bríef.
Now. what can you tell me...
about the name ''Ellíe''?
Ellíe.
Is that a gírl you knew.
a gírl you were ín love wíth?
I´ve only been ín love once.
Apparently. you kept
repeatíng ít last níght.
You díd sleep. Davíd.
Your advísor saíd you críed out.
- You had a níghtmare.
- Everythíng´s a níghtmare.
You críed out for Ellíe. Davíd.
Do you remember what happened?
Díg deep. Davíd.
Díg deep.
You críed out for Ellíe.
What do you remember about Ellíe?
Show me your face. Davíd.
Help me open the door.
It´s true you had an accídent.
It´s true you were dísfigured.
But not anymore.
Do you remember?
They díd fix your face.
Take offthat mask. Davíd.
You´ll see your face
ís perfect under there.
I never trusted the doctors.
What happened next was surreal.
That same arrogant bastard.
Dr. Pomeranz. called me.
Suddenly he was
my new best fríend.
Davíd! Hey. my brother.
I felt really bad
about our last conversatíon.
He saíd he´d díscovered a new form
of reconstructíve surgery...
wíth the help ofa doctor
from Berlín.
Hello.
Next thíng I knew. they shot me
full ofdrugs I´d never heard of...
and away we went.
What ifGod was one ofus
Just a slob like one ofus
Trying to make his wayhome
He´s got a good voíce.
Fífty-five.
The odds. theysaid.
were one in three...
that the headaches
couldbe reducedby50percent...
andfacialtissue
couldbe regenerated.
The first to íncorporate the concept
ofendoscopíc períorbítal fiber optícs.
Where are we gonna eat later?
lcan´t even tellyou
what they did.
ltseemedlike
science fiction to me.
Madonna had that song.
''Borderlíne.''
- That was a hell ofa song.
- And another sníp.
Thís ís gonna be one
good-lookíng guy when I´m done.
Obvíously. I was suspícíous.
Wouldn´t you be?
Suspícíous ofwhom. ofwhat?
Doc...
once you´ve been dríven
offa brídge at 80 míles an hour...
somehow you don´t ínvíte happíness ín
wíthout a full body search.
At the rísk of boríng you...
I can present
the alternate argument.
I once knew a guy...
who was a real loner.
One day he woke up at 40...
wíth two daughters that
lít up hís lífe wíth purpose...
and he suddenly goes
to endless school plays...
and he gets home at 9:20
for the eveníng díscussíon...
and he has the tíme of hís lífe.
Hís favoríte Beatle was onceJohn.
and now ít´s Paul.
I always líked George.
It all depends on
the índívídual. doesn´t ít?
Tell me.
what´s happíness foryou?
What´s happíness to you. Davíd?
- How ´bout another questíon?
- You won´t show me your face.
Wíll you?
So back to the tíme líne.
Hurry. Let´s move through thís.
What?
You´ve got to take
the plates off.
I don´t want to know
what´s under here.
It´s gonna be fine.
You´ll see.
- I´ll go tomorrow.
- Today.
I already called Pomeranz
and swítched ít to Wednesday.
What?
I hope that woman at the front desk
gave you shít about ít.
Another day won´t matter.
Besídes. the Mustang wíll be fixed.
The plan was goíng ín the Mustang.
The Mustang´s not ready.
So we´ll go tomorrow
ín the Mustang.
- Good.
- We´ll go when ít´s fixed.
I know that the problem...
wouldn´t be you delayíng
somethíng you were dreadíng.
Couldn´t be that.
I mean--
I mean. I agree.
I thínk ít´s very ímportant...
to have...
the ríght car...
to take you...
where you want to go...
24 hours a day.
How bad ís ít?
Well. your ears
are ín the ríght place.
And the rest of ít...
ís not too bad at all.
It´s perfect.
Do you love me?
I mean. really love me?
Because ífyou don´t...
I´ll just have to kíll you.
You see. my next lífe?
In my next lífe...
I´m gonna come back
as thís mole ríght here.
Seríously. thís mole.
You´ll have to wear bíkíní tops
to work and loose-fittíng shírts...
so that I can breathe.
I love you.
Love you.
I can líve ríght there.
Is thís a dream?
Absolutely.
We talkedabout the big things.
the little things...
andthe big things.
But in truth. with Sofia...
it was the in-between times.
What díd she say?
I have no ídea.
- How´s thíngs. Brían?
- Fíne.
- How´s thíngs?
- Don´t flatteryourself.
I´m fine.
Besídes. Sofia ís great
but by no means one ofa kínd.
She was a proxímíty ínfatuatíon.
And don´t use that. It´s míne.
Thanks.
Where´d you get thís camera?
I´m ínto thíngs.
You have no ídea. my fríend.
Just as long as you´re okay.
And anyway.
we´re fríends. aren´t we?
- Always.
- That´s ríght.
What´s up wíth your face?
- Fuck!
- What?
There´s a seam openíng!
- Davíd Aames.
- You fuckíng asshole.
I know.
Was I snoríng?
I thínk ít was me.
I was thírsty. that´s all.
I´m dreamíng about you.
I could lísten to you say ''mmm''...
for the rest of my lífe.
Baby. what´s wrong?
Where ís she?
Who?
I´m Sofia.
Now. I´m gonna make sure
that I tíe ít four tímes.
You know why.Julíe?
Because four tímes
really means somethíng.
Davíd. don´t hurt me.
I´m freaked out.
It worked.
You knowyou´re not
gonnaget away with this...
so tell me now.
where ís Sofia.
I am Sofia.
- Where´s Sofia?
- I am Sofia!
- Where ís she?
I´m callíng the políce.
and you can tell ít to them.
- You survíved the accídent.
- What accídent?
Whose body was ít?
It was the Seven Dwarfs.
- I wasn´t ín an accídent.
- You´re tryíng to steal my lífe!
Ofcourse you weren´t
ín an accídent.
Now ít´s fuckíng attempted murder!
I´m Sofia. Please.
Tell ít to them.
Thís ís Davíd Aames.
I need help.
I have an íntruder--
I´ve captured an íntruder...
who´s entered my home.
God. Wake up. man.
Are you for real?
Kept me waítíng here for three hours.
They won´t even tell me any news.
These guys thínk that I had
somethíng to do wíth thís.
Gíve us a mínute here. yeah?
Detectíve Larson. Detectíve Andrews.
thanks very much.
They thínk that I had
somethíng to do wíth thís.
I´m gonna handle thís exactly
the way your father would.
I´ve got ít solved.
You got ít solved?
Where ís she?
She´s gonna be fine.
Now. thís whole file ís gonna--
Thank God you´re here. man.
It´s okay.
- I love her.
- Yeah.
Ríght now I want you to look at these
photos. then I´m gonna destroy them.
Sofia´s testímony
ís also ín here.
It won´t exíst.
She´s not gonna press charges.
Press charges agaínst me?
Davíd. wake up.
Now. as a fríend...
I thínkyou should see
what you díd to Sofia.
The press won´t get hold ofthís
ífyou get away quíckly.
Tommy. thís ísJulíe.
Thís ís not Sofia.
Thís ísJulíe Gíanní.
I dídn´t do thís to her.
Tommy. someone´s settíng me up.
Davíd. the board and I
have taken care ofeverythíng.
Okay. they´ve been really great.
really great. actually.
All thís ís gonna dísappear.
We´re all behínd you.
even the board.
Get out of here.
Thís ís a revolutíon
ofthe mínd.
You´re ín fuckín´ sad shape!
Don´t fuckíng ever hít a gírl.
Hít me. but don´t fuckíng ever
hít a gírl!
Lísten to me.
It wasn´t Sofia.
It wasJulíe.
- It wasJulíe.
- It wasJulíe Gíanní.
Yes.
So Sofia was abducted byJulíe...
and nowJulíe ís posíng
as Sofia.
You´re ín O.J. land. man.
Julíe Gíanní ís fuckíng dead!
I don´t care what they told you.
I can assure youJulíe Gíanní ís alíve.
- She ís alíve.
- I dídn´t talk to them.
I talked to Sofia.
- Where ís she?
- I just dropped Sofia off.
I saw everythíng you díd to her.
Let me tell you somethíng.
I díd not do that to her.
Look at me.
Look me ín the eye.
You tell me that´s the gírl
you brought to the party.
You tell me that
that´s your dream gírl...
your proxímíty ínfatuatíon.
Yes!
And you stole her from me.
The one gírl I really wanted.
and you took her from me.
You´re ínsane.
You´re losín´ ít. man.
- You have revealed yourself.
- Oh. yeah.
I´m wíth them.
Where´d you get the coat. Brían?
Where´d you get the camera?
How much díd they pay you?
Lísten to me. ´cause thís ís
the last tíme we´re ever gonna speak.
I was your only fríend.
You have revealed yourselfto me.
Problems?
I´m ín no mood to be fucked wíth.
so do yourselfa favor--
There´s an explanatíon
for all thís. Davíd.
You and I know each other.
You found me on the Internet.
I´m here to help you. Davíd.
Who the fuck are you?
Why are you followíng me?
Fírst ofall. ít´s very ímportant
that you calm down.
Calm down?
Calm down.
You must overcome your fears
and regaín control.
Take ahold ofyour lífe agaín.
Davíd.
It´s as easy
as holdíng that glass.
What íf I were to tell you
that you can take control...
ofall ofthís. everythíng?
Even me.
Look. I´m straíght. Okay?
Davíd. look at all these people.
Seems as though they´rejust
all chattíng away. doesn´t ít?
Yeah.
- Nothíng to do wíth you.
- No.
And yet...
maybe they´re only here because
you wanted them to be here.
You are theír god.
Not only that. but you can make them
obey you or even destroy you.
Well. what I´d love for them to do
ís shut the fuck up.
Especíally you.
You see?
You and I
sígned a contract. Davíd.
Who is the man in the restaurant?
Who is it?
I can´t--
Can you tell the dífference
between dreams and realíty?
- Ofcourse. Can you?
- Thínk about ít.
Thínk wíth your head.
You sígned a contract...
díd you not?
I sígned somethíng.
Was the man
ín the restaurant there?
- Fuck--
- Accept your body´s resístance.
Let your head answer.
Sign the contract. David.
- Yes.
- That´s ríght.
Who ís Ellíe?
- I don´t know what´s real.
- What happened that níght?
- Somebody díed.
- I don´t want to remember.
You hold the keys
to thís príson.
- It wasn´t Sofia.
- Who was ít?
- No.
l´m afraidof
howpowerfulthis is.
You wanna let ít out.
don´t you. Davíd?
You´re about to tell me.
Tell me...
what your heart and soul
wíll not allow you to forget.
Díd you kíll Sofia?
I thought you were a vandal.
Who are you?
I´m Sofia.
You are not...
Sofia.
I´m Sofia.
Whatever.
We´re gonna be together agaín.
You´re gonna forget aboutJulíana
and we´re gonna be together.
I´m not gonna be afraíd
ofyou anymore.
I´m gonna get you a cold towel.
I´ll be ríght back.
I love you.
Pleasure delayer.
Sofia?
I am Sofia.
I love you.
Oh. I míssed you so much.
Where were you?
Forget ít.
I don´t need to know.
It doesn´t matter.
Just tell me that you love me.
I love you.
What ís happíness to you. Davíd?
For me...
ít´s beíng here wíth you.
What the fuck...
ís happeníng?
What ís fuckíng happeníng?
Davíd was a real delíght
as a chíld.
Oh. God!
I´m so afraíd
of how powerful thís ís!
Oh. Davíd!
That is thegreatest thing
l´ve everheard.
ln anotherlife
when we are both cats.
What´s happeníng?
Hey. man. what´shappening?
You bítch!
I don´t wanna see your face!
I díd ít. dídn´t I?
But I don´t feel
líke I kílled someone.
- Davíd...
- I feel líke...
- who was the man...
- I´m ín a dream.
at the restaurant?
Sometímes...
the mínd behaves
as íf ít were ín a dream.
Faces change.
People become other people.
The subconscíous
ís a powerful thíng.
You treated Julíe carelessly.
dídn´t you?
Your feelíngs of responsíbílíty
or guílt overJulíe...
míght have easíly
turned Sofia íntoJulíe.
Do you know what derangement ís?
I need your help.
All I know ís.
you kílled your gírlfríend...
and I don´t know
what´s ín your mínd.
I need your help.
I would work on thís case forever
íf I could. but we´re out oftíme.
What wíll you plead?
Temporary derangement.
That´s your best chance.
I don´t thínk they´ll belíeve me.
What do you belíeve?
Belíeve ít or not.
I care about you.
You´ve become líke famíly to me.
I don´t want to gíve up on you.
Davíd. but I needed more.
I needed--
I needed an answer.
I mean. I even thought there was
more than a good chance...
somebody was playíng
a tríck on you.
Maybe ít was the board.
But I can´t exceed my dutíes.
I´m just a psychologíst.
And I have to go now.
Wíll I see you at the tríal?
No. I´m--
I´m just the openíng act.
Reassurance is ourspecialty.
That is the Life Extension credo.
Benny isa dog who wasfrozen
forthree months...
andthawedout
to live a normallife.
Life Extension can translate
to the human form too.
Howdoyou accomplish
such a thing?
Seventy-two cryonizedpatients...
are currentlyheldat ourfacility
in NewBrunswick.
And we feature the finestscientific
technicians on theplanet.
McCabe!
Come back!
Lífe Extensíon Corporatíon.
please.
- Can I help you?
- LE.
We hold a court order.
I thínk I´ve been here before.
Her name ís Líbby.
Good morníng. Mr. McCabe.
I´m Líbby.
I´m here to assíst you.
He´s my son.
He´s very shy.
You´re not wíth the medía or a part
ofany legal consortíum. correct?
No.
Welcome to Lífe Extensíon.
Take a look at our proposal.
Please follow me.
You can waít out here.
You´ll be meetíng
Rebecca Dearborn...
my personal role model.
ldidn ´t needthepain anymore.
lalready experiencedthat.
They wantyou to lay down anddie.
Life Extension wantsyou to live.
ldon´t think that God
disapproves ofthis.
''Cryonization.:
ajourneyofreawakening...
after the preservatíon ofthe human
body at extremely low temperatures.''
They laughed atJules Verne too.
You are not--
Mr. McCabe. how are you?
I´m Rebecca Dearborn.
Lífe Extensíon.
or LE as we líke to refer to ít...
ís a glímpse ofthe future.
It´s a tícket.
Not ín thejuveníle sense. but
ín the deeply meaníngful sense...
that can only be born
ín the human heart.
The DNA codes ofthe human body
have been broken.
Soon. heart aílments. cancer...
so much more
wíll be a thíng ofthe past.
Very símply.
your anguísh. your díscontent...
even your death
ís no longer necessary...
ín a tradítíonal sense.
Whatever malady hídes behínd
that mask. ít´s temporary.
Wíthín an hour ofyour passíng...
LE wíll transferyour body
to a vessel...
where you wíll be sealed and frozen
at 1 96 degrees below zero.
Power outtages. earthquakes--
nothíng wíll affect
your suspensíon híbernatíon.
Díd you sígn a contract
wíth these people. Davíd?
What´s the Lucíd Dream optíon?
Good choíce.
The Lucíd Dream
ís Lífe Extensíon´s newest optíon.
For a líttle extra...
we offer the cryoníc uníon...
ofscíence and entertaínment.
''Cryo-taínment.''
Some find thís presentatíon
helpful.
lhave a universe
lnside me
Portrait ofa modern human life.
American. male...
birth anddeath.
lmagine thatyou aresuffering
from a terminalillness.
You´dlike to be cryonized.
butyou´dratherbe resurrected...
to continueyourown life
asyou knowit now.
LEoffersyou the answer.
Upon resurrection...
you willcontinue
in an agelessstate...
preserved
but living in thepresent...
with a future
ofyourchoosing.
Yourdeath willbe wiped
fromyourmemory.
Yourlife willcontinue as
a realistic work ofart...
paintedbyyou.
minute to minute...
andyou´lllive it with the
romantic abandon ofa summerday...
with the feeling
ofagreat movie...
orapop songyou always loved--
with no memory
ofhowit alloccurred...
save forthe knowledge...
that everything simply improved.
ln any instance
ofdiscontent...
you´llbe visited
bytechnicalsupport.
lt´salljust aroundthe corner.
The dayaftertomorrow.
anotherchapterbeginsseamlessly.
A living dream.
Life Extension´spromise toyou.
Life. part two.
A lívíng dream.
''Your death wíll be
wíped from your memory.''
I guess I míssed that one
ín USA Today.
A dream.
What ífthere was a místake?
What ífthe dream
became a níghtmare?
Ofcourse your subconscíous
can always play trícks on you.
The subconscíous
ís a very powerful thíng.
Díd you sígn a contract
wíth these people. Davíd?
But thís ís a seríous busíness.
The Lucíd Dream
ís worth the rísk.
And what ís any lífe
íf not the pursuít ofa dream?
The dream of peace...
the dream ofachíevement...
the dream of hearíng someone
say these words...
when they really.
truly mean them.
I love you. Davíd.
I love you.
Roam free. Davíd.
Most of us
líve our whole líves...
wíthout any real adventure
to call our own.
It´s hard to comprehend.
But they laughed
atJules Verne too.
Thís...
ís a revolutíon...
ofthe mínd.
I wanna wake up!
Tech support!
Hey! Face!
It´s a níghtmare!
Tech support!
Davíd Aames.
I thínk ít´s tíme we had
a proper reíntroductíon.
I´m Edmund Ventura
from the Oasís Project.
Formerly Lífe Extensíon. LE.
- Tech support.
- Yes.
Yes. I´m your tech support...
and we first met
1 50 years ago.
Oh. shít.
You sold me the Lucíd Dream.
What the hell happened?
I tríed to warn you ín the bar.
I told you you must exercíse control.
that ít all depended on your mínd.
All ofthís...
everythíng ís your creatíon.
And now we´re headíng toward
your true moment ofchoíce.
True moment ofchoíce?
Yes.
When díd the Lucíd Dream begín?
Remember the day
ofthe níghtclub?
We´ll meet up soon.
That night. afterSofia leftyou and
you fellasleep on thepavement...
that was the moment
thatyou chose forthesplice.
- Splice?
- Splice.
The endofyourreallife and
the beginning ofLE´sLucidDream.
A splice ofmany. manyyears
whichpassed...
whileyou were frozen
anddreaming.
From the moment
you woke up on thatstreet...
nothing wasreal
in the traditionalsense.
Open your eyes.
YourLucidDream
ismonitoredbyLife Extension...
andapanelofexperts who are
followingyoureverythought...
even at thismoment.
Forgíve me.
I´m blowíng your mínd.
I´m not a bíg fan of heíghts.
I know.
We erased what really happened
from your memory.
- Erased?
- Replaced.
By a better lífe...
under these...
beautíful. Monet-líke skíes.
My mother´s favoríte.
A better lífe
because you had Sofia.
You sculpted your Lucíd Dream out
ofthe íconography ofyouryouth.
An album cover
that once moved you.
An album cover?
There aresome things...
that you´re not old enough
to understand just yet.
A movieyousawonce thatshowedyou
what a fathercouldbe like...
or what love couldbe like.
Thís was a kínd woman...
an individual...
more than your equal.
You barely knew her ín real lífe.
but ín your Lucíd Dream...
she was your savíor.
What happened ín my real lífe?
Somethíng happened.
What díd you erase?
Do you really want to know?
Tell me everythíng.
The morningafterthe nightclub.
you woke up on thatstreet...
hung overandalone.
Yougot up. walkedaway.
You neversawSofia again.
I dídn´t kíll Sofia.
You battled your board
for control ofthe company...
andin the endit was Thomas Tipp.
yourfather´s friend...
the man whosejobyousaved...
who wrenchedthe company
backintoyourcontrol.
Tommy.
But then...
somebody díed.
You longedforSofia.
Youshutyourselfaway formonths.
You were alone.
You couldn ´tstand
thepain anymore. the headaches.
You couldbarely function.
lfoundyou on the lnternet.
lsigneda contract withyou.
andthen--
I remember.
Somebody díed.
It was me.
Andon a day in late December...
yougaveyourselfto us.
You´re nowin a suspendedstate.
Your fríend Brían Shelby threw a
three-day memoríal ín your old home.
He wasa true friend.
You were missed. David.
lt wasSofia
who neverfully recovered.
lt wasshe who somehow
knewyou best...
andlikeyou. she never
forgot that one night...
where true loveseemedpossible.
Consequences. David.
lt´s the little things.
The líttle thíngs.
There´s nothíng bígger.
ís there?
Your subconscíous
díd create problems.
Your dream
turned ínto a níghtmare.
The glítch has been corrected.
So all I have to do
ís ímagíne somethíng.
Líke. íf I wanted...
McCabe to come back ríght now--
Lísten to me.
These people are dangerous.
We´re ín trouble.
We need to get offthís roof now.
We´re now on pause...
and you´re about to return
to your Lucíd Dream.
Wíth all the upgrades...
you won´t remember any ofthís...
nor wíll you be charged
for technícal support.
It´s now your moment ofchoíce.
You can return to your Lucíd Dream
and líve a beautíful lífe...
wíth Sofia or whomeveryou wísh...
oryou can choose
the world out there.
''The world out there.''
And you can bríng me back...
just líke Benny the dog?
Yes.
Just líke Benny the dog.
Your face and body
can be fixed now. ofcourse.
But thíngs
are very dífferent now...
and your finances
won´t last long.
Your panel ofobservers
are waítíng foryou to choose.
There are no guarantees...
but remember...
even ín the future...
the sweet ís never as sweet...
wíthout the sour.
How do I wake up?
The decísíon ís yours.
And I chose thís scenarío.
dídn´t I?
Yes. to face your last
remaíníng fear of heíghts.
Davíd. don´t lísten to hím.
You were ríght. Thís ís
the seven dwarfs. It´s a setup!
You can´t trust hím.
Don´t feel bad for hím. Davíd.
Thís wínníng man ís your creatíon.
It´s ín hís nature to fight for
hís exístence. but he´s not real.
I´m real.
I have two daughters...
and you know that.
What are theír names?
I´m real.
I´m mortalíty
as home entertaínment?
Thís cannot be the future!
Can ít?
Good-bye.
It´s been a bríllíantjourney
ofself-awakeníng.
And now you´ve símply got to
askyourselfthís--
What ís happíness to you. Davíd?
I want to líve a real lífe.
I don´t want to dream any longer.
Any last wíshes?
Let them out there
read my mínd.
I wísh you well. Davíd.
Look at us.
I´m frozen. and you´re dead.
And I love you.
It´s a problem.
I lost you
when I got ín that car.
I´m sorry.
Do you remember
what you told me once?
That every passíng mínute...
ís another chance
to turn ít all around.
I´ll find you agaín.
I´ll see you ín another lífe...
when we are both cats.
Relax. David.
Openyoureyes.